<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TheHumanTaurch @ DBC</title>
    <description>Chronicling the adventures of our fearless heroine as she embarks on her quest to become a junior developer.</description>
    <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thehumantaurch.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 11:52:01 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 11:52:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Combining Rails and Angular</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;or-masochism-in-learning&quot;&gt;Or: Masochism in Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I know Ruby. I know Rails. I cut my teeth in Sinatra, so I appreciate what Rails does for me and how bulky it is. I know JavaScript, too. I love how elegant Ruby is, but sometimes, and I hate to admit it, I think JavaScript is the future because it’s so much faster. So I struck out on this journey to learn Angular. But I sort of hate Node/Mongo. So I’m keeping Rails/Postgres and combining the two. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a lot to think about though. How do you make sure that Angular on the front end talks to Rails on the back end? Here are the things you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//tech/2015/02/28/the-rails-angular-combo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//tech/2015/02/28/the-rails-angular-combo/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Myth of the Female Prodigy</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-how-its-hurting-women-in-tech&quot;&gt;And How It’s Hurting Women In Tech&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a woman in both tech and performing arts, I think a lot about the representations of women in both fields. When we were dealing with the fallout from &lt;a href=&quot;http://kotaku.com/ubisoft-cut-plans-for-female-assassins-in-unity-1589278349&quot;&gt;Ubisoft deciding not to make female characters available in multiplayer for Assassin’s Creed Unity&lt;/a&gt;, I would painstakingly explain to anyone who asked, and many who didn’t, why video game representations are a chicken and egg scenario. Do women not play video games because they don’t like video games or because they don’t see themselves represented in video games? The same can be said of a black person preferring to play a sports game as opposed to a fantasy RPG. For me, it was a very tangible experience seeing Sailor Jupiter, a girl who was brunette and had a ponytail just like me. For a girl who didn’t like pink and wasn’t blonde, there were few stories and representations of superheroes that I could relate to. The fact is that those of us who are “minorities” that play video games where we’re not represented (or read comics or whatever), we do that &lt;em&gt;in spite of&lt;/em&gt; the differences and not because of them, as most white males do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me back to the point of this post. There &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; representations of females in tech. They’re few and far between, but they’re there. &lt;strong&gt;However&lt;/strong&gt;, where we do find them, they are incredibly gifted prodigies. The first that comes to mind for me is Felicity Smoak from &lt;em&gt;Arrow&lt;/em&gt;, and Maggie Masden from &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;/em&gt;. These girls are both incredibly hot &lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt; incredibly gifted hackers. And it’s not just Hollywood that says so, it’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Felicity_Smoak&quot;&gt;also&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://tfwiki.net/wiki/Maggie_Madsen&quot;&gt;cannon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, not all women can be prodigious hackers, or blond (why are they always blond?!). When women are few and far between in tech, are hiring managers waiting and hoping they’ll find such a prodigy as opposed to investing in a woman who’s a decent coder and hard worker? There are representations of average male coders and prodigious male coders in the news and media all the time. So when a hiring manager is confronted with two candidates, an above average male coder and an average female coder, who is he going to pick? While he may want more women on his team, does he want to invest the time and money in bringing the average coder up to speed? Or would he rather wait until a supremely gifted woman comes along? This isn’t explicit in his mind by any means. It’s just that there’s no affirmative action requirement in your average job placement. But when women often have to overcome a lot more to be strong candidates in the tech field and have the same support, the myth of the female prodigy can definitely hurt them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that what I’m saying is one of those subtle, implicit forms of sexism that would be near impossible to study. But &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.attn.com/stories/1003/women-leaving-tech-sexism&quot;&gt;we know&lt;/a&gt; that there is still a serious sexixm problem in the tech world, and, to quote the linked attn: article, “the attitudes holding [women] back [are] far more subtle and therefore far harder to challenge on any grand scale”. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//tech/2015/02/25/heroes-like-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//tech/2015/02/25/heroes-like-me/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going from STEM to STEAM</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;or-the-value-of-an-artistic-background-in-tech&quot;&gt;Or: The Value of an Artistic Background in Tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been some talk recently of trying to go from talking about STEM to talking about STEAM. As someone who has gone from the “A” to the “T”, it unfortunately rings true that a lot of the skills I’ve learned from working in the arts, skills so deeply ingrained in me that I don’t even think of them as skills anymore, aren’t widely present in the tech world. Why should you hire an artist? Here are a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working-together&quot;&gt;Working Together&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, you can learn teamwork through being on a sports team, but there’s a certain sense of dependency in the arts that you don’t necessarily get on a sports team. You can’t always pass it off to that one guy or girl who could almost always score. And no one could accuse you of not contributing as much if you were playing defense. In an orchestra, every instrument matters equally. If you don’t do your job, and everyone around you doesn’t do their job, things fall apart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working-solo&quot;&gt;Working Solo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, artists can work alone and have to know how to work alone, too. You can’t audition as a group. Your skills are your own. But this ties back into the working as a team: if you don’t know and practice your part, the group can’t succeed. Another actor in the cast cannot learn your lines and do your part. When working in the arts, when given a job you enter into a contract, written or unwritten, that you trust everyone else to do their job, and everyone trusts you to do yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;constant-learning&quot;&gt;Constant Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You think you know it all? An artist generally won’t get too far with that kind of attitude. Every new person you work with is a chance to learn in the arts. Kevin Spacey, who’s won ALL the awards, wouldn’t go into a working on a scene with Dame Judi Dench, who has won more than ALL the awards, and think he had nothing to gain from working with her. Every project presents its own new challenges, and a chance to find a new weakness. Which leads us to …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comfort-with-uncertainty&quot;&gt;Comfort with Uncertainty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how successful an artist becomes, they’re unlikely to forget the hard times. Those times when they weren’t sure where they were getting their next paycheck and whether or not they could make rent. Uncertainty is a huge part of life for an artist. They’ve waited to hear about auditions and never gotten a response. They’ve gotten their 6 AM call time at 12:30 AM and changed their schedule to accomodate it. They’ve been bumped up to first string at the last minute and felt they had the world riding on their shoulders. They know how to deal with stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comfort-with-sudden-changes&quot;&gt;Comfort with Sudden Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artists generally aren’t at the top of the totem pole. They’re usually the low man. They can have opinions and feelings, but they usually don’t get to have much say or agency in how something is done. They’re usually the last person to find something out that specifically deals with them. They’ve accepted this. They’re used to it. When you change the lines on opening night, they shut up and learn them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;they-know-the-show-must-go-on&quot;&gt;They Know the Show Must Go On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If nothing else, an artist knows not to let the perfect be the enemy of the good. If you get sick on opening night, you probably have to suck it up. If you really can’t, everyone else helps your understudy get through. They’re problem solvers. When a prop breaks onstage, they improvise. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say that artists don’t whine, that they don’t have diva moments or don’t crumble under pressure.  But when deployment is about to happen and a new bug is found, just know that an artist has probably been in that situation before. They’ll feel the pressure, but they’ll flow with it. They might not come up with the best solution, but it’ll work for the time being. They’ll talk with the team, but take it upon themselves to make sure a solution is found. So thank your lucky stars when you meet an artist who wants to work for you. They’re used to overcoming adversity, and they’ll be sure to do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//tech/2015/01/20/stem-to-steam/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//tech/2015/01/20/stem-to-steam/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>And now for phase 2!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-last-we-met-our-hero&quot;&gt;When Last We Met Our Hero…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So. I’ve finally passed phase 1 everyone. This is fantastic news. Things are mostly the same here except, of course, things are harder. We’re starting to put things in actual web pages now. Crazy, right? We’re using a framework, Sinatra (which is like a baby version of Rails). But real talk: HTTP routing is complicated. If you didn’t follow any of that, that’s okay. I’m still not following it either. I hope that’s because it’s only day 2 (of phase 2), and most people I talk to says learning routing is probably the hardest part of DBC. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else? Yoga is on Mondays/Wednesdays now (and optional, but really: why wouldn’t I do yoga???). My new cohort is cool. Cohorts are students that come in at the same time and go through the three phases (3 weeks each) of DBC together. If you repeat, you switch cohorts. I used to be part of the Great Horned Owls, but now I’m a member of the Mud Turtles. This may sound like a demotion, but the people, for the most part, are WAY more awesome AND we’re now evenly divided between men and women which I’m pretty sure has never happened before in the history of DBC!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the cohorts have their own call– the Red Spotted Newts from a few cohorts back referenced Monty Python (look it up), and the Owls referenced Missy Elliot’s lyrics (Hootie Hoo! Run for cover…), but I am proud to say I came up with the Mud Turtles’ call. So I will leave you with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Coders in a bash shell, TURTLE POWER!’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(It may be one of the nerdiest things I’ve ever done, but… &lt;em&gt;brushes shoulders off&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/09/17/phase-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/09/17/phase-2/</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Post Month 1 Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-last-we-met-our-hero&quot;&gt;When Last We Met Our Hero…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was week 1 of phase 1 of Dev Bootcamp! After 9 weeks of grueling self-study she was finally in New York City studying in person. Spirits were high!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-pledge&quot;&gt;The Pledge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things were cool back in week 1, before we got into object-oriented design, before databases and Active Record. Things were hard, and they got harder, but at some point (maybe on Sudoku day, maybe on Active Record Jr. day), I started to withdraw. For whatever reason (and I have a few theories) my confidence plummeted, and I started acting as if everything was okay when it really wasn’t. This, of course, turned into a vicious cycle of lower confidence, more withdrawal, and less learning. DBC makes a point of wanting you to constantly be uncomfortable, but also acknowledge if that discomfort turns to drowning. I was drowning, but I didn’t ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can probably see where this is going. A week ago today I sat down after yoga to take my final assessment for phase 1, and it did not go well. It could partially have been a self-fulfilling prophecy, my own gender discrimination (yes, I’m sexist, too), that I really wasn’t feeling well, that I panicked, or maybe a combination of all of the above, but whatever it was: I choked. And while I knew the material, I didn’t really KNOW the material. I hadn’t owned it, yet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-turn&quot;&gt;The Turn&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bad News: I failed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DBC doesn’t call it that, of course, but it still felt like it. I was asked to repeat phase 1. Friday was terrible, and Monday might have been worse (seeing your friends go on to new material and you’re with brand new people who all know each other starting back at “GO” and not having collected $200). I said I’d be okay with it, and when it came down to it, I realized there was no way I could have really prepared myself to be okay with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-prestige&quot;&gt;The Prestige&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned more about myself in the weekend between Phase 1, Take 1 and Phase 1, Take 2 and the past few days than I have in awhile. I learned how hard it is for me to advocate for myself. I learned that there were some people in my cohort(class) that were really intimidating me, and that was hard to admit. I learned that I had started doubting myself even before things got rough, and I hadn’t even noticed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned how to ask for and accept help. I also learned that I knew the material better than I thought, but I wasn’t breaking problems down enough. I also learned what I didn’t learn in the first three weeks, and I’m working on remedying that now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new cohort is a much better environment for me, and my teachers are answering my questions (mostly because I’m actually asking them). The feedback I gave to the school has really been implemented. This is all the Good News. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-other-bad-news&quot;&gt;The Other Bad News&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, you guessed it– I won’t be back on October 4 anymore :( . Not only that, I won’t be back in time to do the dance workshop I signed up for with Sonya Tayeh. And also… there was a haircut… that went about 2 inches shorter than expected… it’s shoulder length. It was(still is) traumatic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BUT things are way better this time around. I’m learning a lot more, and getting a lot more help, and working with people who are as a group more awesome than the group I was in last time. I’ve realized that more than anything I get intimidated even when I know the material, and that intimidation is paralyzing. It’s hard to overcome, but I’m working on it. Also, I get to see more friends in NYC now :) &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/08/28/phase-1-take-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/08/28/phase-1-take-1/</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 1 Reflection</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-1-reflection&quot;&gt;Week 1 Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When have you chosen not to expose your ignorance, and what impact did it have on your effectiveness?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing about working in the arts is that there is no such thing as a sure thing. I’ve become more and more comfortable with not knowing everything. I’m used to failure, too. I’ve adapted to the learning lifestyle. There’s a pressure that comes with working people who are “stronger” than you, but it’s a necessary evil. If they’re worth working with, they’ll help you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find my biggest problem when I pretend I don’t know something is the fear that comes along with it. When will it come out that I don’t know? And most often there’s also the fear of what the worst possible answer could be. Why I ever willingly put myself through that is a mystery because it feels awful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the 5 things you feel like you understand the least about computer programming? Try to keep it to stuff that you’ve tried to understand in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recursion(algorithms)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attr_reader/writer/etc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Private vs. Public&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seeing things in an object oriented way as opposed to a functional way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the way you feel most comfortable exposing your ignorance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer to do it in the moment in person when it comes to material (if I think of the question), but it usually takes me some time to process something enough to form the question I need to ask. In those (more frequent) cases, the problem is whether or not I remember the question once I figure it out. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/08/10/week1-reflection/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/08/10/week1-reflection/</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Post Week 1 Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;phase-1-week-1&quot;&gt;Phase 1: Week 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since a bunch of my friends are awesome and want to know how it’s going, I thought I’d send this to all of you instead of replying. Efficiency is the name of the game right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-morning&quot;&gt;The Morning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day starts at 5:30-5:45 AM (depending on whether I hit snooze… which I usually do). I take about half an hour to get ready and am out the door by 6:15 (eating breakfast in the car) to get on the 6:32 express train from New Haven to Grand Central. I usually manage to get about a half hour of sleep on the train around reviewing stuff for the day. I get to NYC around 8:15 and hop on the 4/5/6 down to Wall Street. My school is two blocks from the Stock Exchange. I usually stop for coffee at the Dunkin’ Donuts in our building before going up to class. We’re supposed to be there at 8:45 but my usual arrival time is 8:50 because of the train schedule stuff. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-school-dayweek&quot;&gt;The School Day/Week&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day starts with a lecture or yoga, depending on the day of the week, about an hour long. Then it’s coding for two and a half hours in assigned pairs until lunch at 12:30. Lunch goes until 2– 1.5 hours sounds good, but you’re usually scarfing in order to A) finish your work from the morning, or B) catching a few Zzs in the nap room (just a room with the lights off that you grab a corner in to curl up and pass out on the hard floor). After lunch there’s a school-wide meeting. There are announcements and stuff, and usually a terrible joke that gets a slow clap. We then go right back into coding, or maybe another brief lecture and then coding straight until 6. The gong rings (tolls?), except nobody leaves at 6. If anything, you reevaluate with your partner and see how long you think you both need to stay (but the building closes at 2 AM). There are special things scattered throughout the week– we have an Engineering Empathy lecture once a week, and Wednesdays are days you can chose your own partner or work by yourself. Fridays we have check-ins as small groups and the whole school. There’s meditation at 12 on 3 days a week, too, and psychologist counselor to talk to, and two career counselors you can see at any time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no email. There is no Facebook. There are no phones. Sometimes people check them at lunch, but for the most part, we forget such things exist. I’m a hard person to get ahold of, and I’m sorry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-nights&quot;&gt;The Nights&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I’m the slacker in the group (my cohort already has a bad reputation for working too hard in week 1 and being too competitive though, so hopefully that will change) that only stays until 8 at the latest so I can get the 8:30 train home (during which I read, watch lectures, or code), get home by 10:45 and be in bed by 11:30. Wash, rinse, repeat. On Thursday evenings there are talks, and they get us pizza and beer (we have a tap in the common room) if we stay for it. On Friday there’s karaoke, but it started at 9 and I was too tired to go last night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-people&quot;&gt;The People&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone here (with a very few exceptions) is totally awesome. You’re expected to struggle, but everyone is always available to ask questions and very friendly. There’s a guy in my cohort with the same birthday as me… which was awesome until I asked him if he was born in 1989, figuring he was a bit younger than me. HE WAS BORN IN 1991. It’s okay. There’a also a guy who’s five years older than me. I’m the median age. There are 3 girls in my cohort (including me), nine guys. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;and-as-for-me&quot;&gt;And as for me?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m already behind on work– the good news is there’s no shame in repeating a phase (it’s a 3-week section of the 9-week course, and I’d say about a third of students repeat either phases 1 or 2), but obviously I want to get back to DC ASAP, so I’m working as hard as I can. It’s definitely as intense as advertised in most ways. We have our first mock assessments on Monday/Tuesday so I’ll have a better idea then on where I stand. I’m thinking commuting from New Haven will be okay for phases 1 and 2 and then for phase 3 I’ll have to stay in NYC. Now that I’ve adjusted to life here (sort of… kind of… well, not really, but it’s something), I’m hoping to FINALLY see friends. Maybe after I pass phase 1 I’ll be able to come to DC for a weekend, but it’s a long trip and weekends require A LOT of work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Mom is saving my butt big time by driving me to and from the train station and helping me with grocery shopping and packing lunches– I’m not lazy, I’m just working THAT much. In fact, I’d write more details, but I have to get back to work! Hope all is well where you’re at, folks. Talk soon :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/08/09/phase1-week1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/08/09/phase1-week1/</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 9 Cultural Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-9&quot;&gt;Week 9&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-ask-or-not-to-ask&quot;&gt;To Ask, or Not To Ask&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know who knew how to ask the big, tough questions? The ones that get right to the heart of the matter and don’t mess around? Well, if the header was any indication, you know where I’m going with this: Hamlet, or rather, Master William Shakespeare. Okay, so maybe he wasn’t exactly economical with his words (he WAS a poet after all), but “To be or not to be? That is the question.” really cuts to the quick. This brings us to our first pro-tip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asking Questions Tip # 1: Don’t Mess Around&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t equivocate. Don’t ramble on. Don’t make excuses. You have every right to ask the question you’re asking, and the person answering it doesn’t need to know why you’re asking. Remember to KISS: Keep It Simple Stupid. They just need the background situation and question, which brings us to our second pro-tip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asking Questions Tip # 2: Know Your Audience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to post on Stack Overflow, you have a wealth of amazing resources at your fingertips. The programmers on Stack Overflow are happy to help, but they’re taking time out of their day to give you a hand. Don’t make them ask you more questions in order to get to an answer for you (though sometimes this is unavoidable). Give them the relevant information such as what language you’re working in, what programs you’re working with and in, what you’re trying to accomplish, and your best guess as to where things are going wrong. Don’t just give them your code and say “help!” either. Asking a question is a conversation, not cheating on a test, which brings us to our final pro-tip:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asking Questions Tip # 3: Don’t Soliloquize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking a question is the BEGINNING of a CONVERSATION. When you’ve answered questions before, what information did you need or use in order to find a solution? Make sure you provide it. Did anything ever frustrated you while you were trying to help someone? Make sure you don’t do it. Follow up with people. Even if it turns out you made a stupid typo, if someone points it out, thank them. If they have a follow up question, answer it. If you have a follow up question, ask it. In other words: be courteous. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I was lying in the beginning: don’t actually emulate Hamlet. He was a lone wolf and he got killed in the end, so he’s not really a great role model for this sort of thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. You know how frustrating it is when you can’t get your code to work and it’s all because of one tiny little comma you left out? For some people, it’s just as frustrating to see commas left out of regular writing. Use them. Use proper spelling. Proofread. You may not care, but the person who may eventually solve your current headache may get a headache from your disdain of the oxford comma and not help you out. Food for thought :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/08/02/week-9-cultural/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/08/02/week-9-cultural/</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 8 Technical Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-8&quot;&gt;Week 8:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-program-a-programming-language&quot;&gt;How to Program a Programming Language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does everything we’re working on… work? Where did Ruby come from, as in how do you program a programming language? For that matter, how do you program a computer? How does a motherboard translate electrical impulses from my keyboard to present the words I type on the screen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look back, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let me make some analogies. We have computers and programming languages. Programming languages are just like the language we speak in our every day lives. As humans, we invented languages to communicate between each other. A programming language is another invention we’ve created to communicate between two types of entities, humans (or users), and computers. In that way, if you think about it, a computer is a prototypical human. Now that we can communicate with computers, we can teach them to do many things. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to that prototypical human to trace how programs and computers came to be. Our brains weren’t developed enough to process language for a long period of human evolution. Sure dogs, cats, monkeys, all animals have their own “language”, but it’s incredibly basic and instinctual. The prototypical human version of the computer is actually a very early calculator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1837, Charles Babbage designed the “Analytical Engine”, or what most people consider the first “modern” computer. It worked by a method of punched cards that had been introduced in 1801 by Joseph Marie Jacquard in his Jacquard Loom. A card punched in a particular pattern would be connected to strings on a loom through hooks, and whether or not the card was punched in a specific place would raise or lower the hooks— a series of cards punched in different places could create beautiful patterns. Babbage’s design of the Analytical machine was to take input punched cards and return a print. The Analytical Engine could handle basic arithmetic through conditional branching and loops (Sound familiar? More on this &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analytical_engine#Instruction_set&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and had integrated memory (numerical constants). Six years later, Ada Lovelace (girl power!) took a description of the machine and translated it, but also added her own notes as to how to repurpose the machine to calculate Bernoulli numbers. She invented a new way to communicate between a machine and its user, and while it was not technically a programming language, the first programming language ever is named after her. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now we start to see how we can get from this: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thehumantaurch.github.io//assets/punchcards-large.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Punchcard Image 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thehumantaurch.github.io//assets/ibm-80-column-punched-card1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Punchcard Image 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then to this: &lt;em&gt;(though it would take a whole different blog post…)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thehumantaurch.github.io//assets/football5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Punchard Image 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we know where it goes from there… &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if humans evolved to process language, computers evolved from processing punched cards to computer chips. Programming languages evolved from a binary system in weaving (i.e. punched or not punched pulled the thread above or below the waft), to incorporate math and loops and booleans further and further into the Rubys, SQLs, JavaScripts, and HTMLs we know and love today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//technical/2014/07/25/week-8-technical/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//technical/2014/07/25/week-8-technical/</guid>
        
        
        <category>technical</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 8 Cultural Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-8&quot;&gt;Week 8&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conflicting-feelings&quot;&gt;Conflicting Feelings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dealing with conflict has never been a strong suit of mine. I didn’t grow up in a house that ever dealt with it in a remotely healthy manner. I was taught to hold in all my feelings so as not to make things worse. This habit is such an innate part of me that I’m having trouble remembering the last time I dealt with conflict. To that end, on the compass of shame I am mainly a massochist and runner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two years ago my parents (well, my father) suggested that I apply to business school. It was a good natured and well intentioned suggestion. I was “too smart” to be doing what I was doing. My father went to business school and my mother minored in business. It shouldn’t have been a problem, except of course as my best friend so eloquently put it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“I’m sorry, have your parents met you?!”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They could have told me to go to law school and I would have said it was pedestrian and obvious and had a million reasons why I shouldn’t go that they would have believed. If they had told me to go to med school, I would say that I wish I could, but my pathologic fear of getting my blood drawn was probably prohibitive. But business school? Wherever I was on the career/mentality/aptitude/personality spectrums (spectra?), business school was at the opposite end. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to laugh it off. My father persisted. I made excuses (suddenly math REALLY wasn’t my thing as opposed to me just preferring languages). My father persisted. There was a good 15 (though probably closer to 20) minute discussion in front of both of my brothers, neither of whom would comment on whether or not they thought business school was a good idea for me (one had just gotten into business school, so he was biased anyway). I eventually turned to my mother and she placidly said that I could do anything I put my mind to. Shocked, and completely taken aback, I wouldn’t let any of them leave the room until the application was completed and done. I blasted through it in about an hour and a half. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conflict obviously had nothing to do with whether or not I could do business school, or even whether or not I should have gone to business school. It was about feeling betrayed, in particular, by my mother. As I was insisting that business school and I would not be a good mix, no one supported me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I acceded. I filled out the application. Until a few days later when I finally blew up at my mother, and by “blew up” I mean “break down in front of” and asked why she thought I would be a good fit at business school because I truly and honestly couldn’t see it for myself. Everyone thought it was a good idea but me, so I was just begging someone to help me see it. My mother’s response? She didn’t honestly think it was a great idea, but it was AN idea and I filled out the application so quickly she figured I must have somehow gotten excited by the idea of going back to school. It was then that I finally got angry. She said if I didn’t want to do it, I needed to learn to say so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouch. And as is so often the case, it hurt because it was true. It was undoubtedly a wake-up call, and I’ve since been more aware of acquiescing simply to keep the peace or putting up with something because it’s “easier” than dealing with the problem. What struck me most, however, was how it took me 3 days or so to articulate the feelings the conflict had stirred in me. I’ve grown up suppressing and delaying how I process those feelings for over 20 years, and it’s a hard habit to break. The awareness at least is a start, and hopefully I can continue to get better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/07/25/week-8-cultural/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thehumantaurch.github.io//culture/2014/07/25/week-8-cultural/</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
